我连糊了三铺
I've won 3 games consecutively.
气得他说不打了
He doesn't wanna play then.
运气来了挡不住，不好意思
Some guy has all the luck!
我就说你准赢
I said you must win.
慢着
Hold it!
敢不敢赌一铺大的？
Have guts to play a big game?
我怕你才怪呢
I won't be scared!
爸，你说说他嘛
Dad, tell him not to!
怕什么呢？他一定赢啊
Don't be afraid? He'll win!
你总是帮着他
You're always on his side.
怎么？敢不敢啊？
What's the matter?
钱够不够？
Enough money?
赢了这铺还多了呢
After this one, definitely.
上，列哥，肯定赢
Take it! You'll win, Rick!
好，赌就赌！
Ok! I accept it!
最后一铺
Last game!
每次你都这么说
You said so every time.
好小子，真行
Good boy!
张伯！
Uncle Cheung!
成哥找你
Big Brother Shing is waiting for you.
成哥！
Big Brother Shing!
他在外边！
He's out there!
别停下来，接着玩
Keep on playing!
不能怪我了，是你老爸让我玩的
It's not my fault! I do as your dad said.
开始了…
Start...
完了…这次完蛋了！
I'm running out of luck.
链子是买不成了
No hope for the gold bracelet.
这是多出来的
These are the excessive.
我叫你买的，买了没有？
Haven't you bought what I told you to?
不用急，在这里
Don't worry. Here it is.
两不欠啦
Now no one owes anything to no one!
成哥，您知道我早就收山啦
Big Brother Shing! You know that retired long ago.
这一次是我儿子
This time it's my son!
你够经验嘛
You're experienced.
不然，我也用不着来求你了
Otherwise, I wouldn't come to see you.
正因为是您儿子
It's because of your son.
我怕万一失了手，我担当不起嘛
I'm afraid that I couldn't handle.
老张，你是怎么搞的吗？
Cheung, what had happened to you?
你以前做事很爽快的
You used to be straightforward!
怎么变得婆婆妈妈呢？
Why are you so sluggish now?
大概我老了吧！
Maybe it's because I'm old!
又不是让你杀人放火
I'm not telling you to murder someone.
只是帮我带个人过来
Just smuggle a boy here for me.
这有什么困难？
What's the difficulty?
你办不到？
Do you refuse me?
这样吧，成哥，我帮您介绍一个人吧
I can introduce you to another guy!
用不着你介绍，我自己没人吗？
No need for that! I've got lots of guy!
要信得过才成嘛
I must find one that is reliable.
自己兄弟，帮还是不帮？
Yes or no?
就算现在我换人帮我，这件事你已经知道了
Even if I find others, you've known this case already.
以后出了漏子，你洗也洗不清啊！
If there's anything wrong later, you'll be suspected!
就勉为其难吧
Don't refuse me!
我看你这儿生意还不错嘛
Your business is good here!
有没有人来闹事啊？
Got any guy making trouble here?
有的话，告诉我一声啊
Tell me if there is any!
谢谢啊！
Thank you!
还生我气啊？
Still be angry about me?
什么意思啊？
What does it mean?
送给你的
It's for you!
你不是说好喜欢这条链子吗？
Haven't you said that you liked it very much?
赌钱赢回来的我不要
I won't take it if it was won from gambling.
别这么小器
Don't be childish!
阿列，来，你过来！
Rick, come over here!
什么事，张伯？
What's the matter, Uncle Cheung?
坐！
Sit down!
怎么了？又跟阿立赌气？
Quarreling again with Lap?
迁就她嘛
She is spoiled.
开玩笑的
Just joking!
阿列，我有点事请你帮帮忙
Rick, I want your help.
什么事？
What can I do for you?
我想让你给我开车
I want you to be my driver!
开车！
Driver!
没问题，什么时候？
No problem! When?
可能会有危险
There maybe danger!
帮一个人偷渡过来
We'll help a guy immigrate illegally.
您张伯的事，没问题，我帮你
I'll do anything for you.
那谢了！
Thank you!
刚才我爸跟你说什么？
What did my dad talk to you?
没什么，我拒绝他了
I rejected his proposal!
拒绝？拒绝他什么？
What have you rejected?
拒绝你啦！他让我娶你
I refused to marry you!
你美丽动人，活泼可爱
You're beautiful and sweet.
温柔体贴，天真无邪，准有帮人运
So kind that you'll bring luck to husband!
可惜我没有福气啊
But I don't have that luck!
链子啊链子，你可真没用了
This chain has no use now!
人家都不要你
No one need you!
你滚蛋吧
Just go away, stupid chain!
你干吗扔掉它？
Why did you throw it away?
我不管，你给我捡回来
Pick it back for me!
不认识我啦？
Don't you know me?
越大越漂亮啦
Getting prettier every day.
你爸爸在家啊
Is your dad home?
老张，好久不见，好吗？
Long time no see, Cheung!
这里还不错
It's not bad here!
生意过得去吧？
How is your business?
还过得去…
So so...
找得我这么急，有什么好关照啊？
Why looking for me in such an urgency?
还不是老买卖
Old trick.
你不是跟我说上岸了吗？
Wasn't you retired already?
帮个朋友吧！
I'm helping a friend!
这不是上水吗？
Isn't here Sheung Shui?
再过去就是元朗啦
We'll be in Yuen Long soon.
我知道，跟着是青山
Then it is Castle Peak.
然后是荃湾，葵涌了
And then Tsuen Wan, Kwai Chung.
张伯，有邓丽君的带子吗？放来听听
Do you have any audio-tape of Theresa Tang?
没有
No.
这是总督牌，美国的嘛
This is Viceroy, an American brand.
我早就抽过了
I've smoked that before.
现在我换牌子，抽万宝路啦
Now I'm a Malboro man.
香港特区也不现代化
Hong Kong is not that modern.
跟深圳差不多
Similar to Shenzhen.
张伯，你这辆车有空调吗？
Does this car have air-conditioner?
我爸爸的“宾司”有空调的
My dad's Benz has air-conditioner!
小老弟，挺机灵的吧
Young man, you're smart!
你来香港一定混得起来
You'll succeed in Hong Kong.
怎么？有没有想过干点什么？
Haven't you thought of doing anything?
我想当歌星，举行演唱会
I want to be a singer.
红磡有个体育馆嘛
Singing in a concert at the Hong Kong Coliseum
以后我就要在那儿唱
some days.
有志气
Good ambition!
不过当歌星要有门路
But you got to have connection to be a singer.
小意思，我老爸一句话就成了
I'll make it with the help of my dad.
你老爸是李嘉诚啊？
Who's he? Lee Ka-shing?
我老爸不是李嘉诚
No, he isn't!
罗万成啊
He's Law Man-shing!
听说过吧
Haven't you heard of him?
干什么？你干什么？
What are you doing?
有警察！
Police!
兄弟，自己人，带他回总部
Take him to the headquarters!
- 自己人啊，开车吧  - 谢谢
- Ok!  - Thanks.
高招啊！
Clever trick!
老张，咱们喝点东西吧？
Let's have some drinks, Cheung?
赶时间啊
We're in a hurry.
还不放开我？
Release me then!
也不急在这一会儿，对吧？
There's no need to hurry!
老弟，在前面杂货铺停下
Young man, stop before the store!
正好，我想喝水
Good, I'm thirsty!
走吧
Let's go.
别那么用力，很痛啊
Be gentle. It's painful.
走吧
Let's go.
阿列，下来喝点汽水
Rick, come and have some drinks!
不用了，我在车上等就行了
No, thanks! I wait here!
麻烦你，两瓶汽水
Two bottles of soft drink!
放开我
Release me!
老张，这可是你不对了
Cheung, you're too selfish.
罗万成的儿子，你居然不告诉我
Why don't you tell me that he's Law's son?
这可是财神爷，你给得这么少？
He's wealthy but you give me so little!
还不带我找我爸爸？
Why don't you take me to my dad?
张伯，你快带我去啊
Take me to my dad at once!
你还在这儿等什么？
What are you still waiting for here?
你想要多少呢？
How much do you want?
至少这个数
At least this figure!
老张，你给我听着啊
Cheung, you listen.
如果捞不到什么油水的话
If I didn't get any benefit
我宁愿把他献上去领功请赏
I'd rather arrest him.
好吧，见了成哥，我跟他说
Ok, I tell Shing when I see him.
现在说好一点
It's better to tell him now!
来
Come!
小老弟，再忍耐一会儿吧
Young man, be patient!
喂，成哥，我是老张
Hello, Brother Shing! It's me, Cheung!
你儿子没事
Your son is alright.
我这位兄弟手头儿有点紧
The cop here wants more money.
请您加点
Can you do that?
没问题吧？
Do you agree?
好…
Ok...
我这个…
I...
好啊，耍我是吗？
Trying to fool me?
有你的，妈的，胆敢耍我！
You cunning old fox.
邓Sir，我不是这个意思
Tang, I didn't mean that...
我是怕把事情弄糟了
I don't want to foul it up.
你还说没有耍我？
Aren't you fooling me?
你信不信我把他带到警局
I'll arrest him.
谁也没便宜的
None of us will benefit from it.
邓Sir，你听我说…
Tang, please listen to me...
你妈的耍浪头？好，我就陪你玩
Don't you try to play tricks.
我现在马上把他带到警察局
I take him to the police station now.
我看你怎么跟成哥交代
I wonder what you can say to Big Brother Shing.
不是…
No...
你他妈的耍我？我就让你耍到底
I call the cards now.
邓Sir，你不要逼我，实际上我是…
Tang, don't drive me too far please! I, really...
你他妈的胆敢抢枪？
You chicken shit.
邓Sir，你为什么要开枪？
Tang, you are in a big trouble.
别动！
Don't move!
你叫我怎么跟罗万成交代啊
How can I explain to Big Brother Shing now?
交代？
Explain?
爸！
Dad!
阿立，快上车！
Lap, get into the car!
我打电话给老王，你在车上等我
I'll phone Wong! Wait for me in the car!
阿列呢？
Where's Rick?
他在码头等我们
He's waiting at the pier!
- 发生什么事？ - 上车再说
- What happened?  - Just get in!
喂，老王！
Hello, Wong!
有没有船？
Have you got any ship?
是啊！
Yes!
出了事啦，要避一避
Something is wrong! We have to hide!
三个人，越快越好
Three! As soon as possible!
爸！
Dad!
阿立，你要上哪儿去？
Lap, where are you going?
我去报警啊！
I call the police!
你不能去，这种事可不能报警啊！
You can't report this case to the police!
那我怎么办呢？
Then what can I do?
快点找人救你爸爸！
Find someone to save your dad!
我找谁啊？
Whom could I ask for help?
找神爷！
Find Godfather Shen!
神爷？
Godfather Shen?
是啊，你爸爸以前跟他合作
Yes, he was your dad's partner once
我看他说不定会帮你
I think he may help you.
请问神爷在吗？
Is Godfather Shen here?
找神爷干什么？
What are you looking him for?
我找他有要事，他在吗？
Something urgent. Is he here?
神爷！
Godfather Shen!
全都湿透啦，偷渡游过来吗？
All wet! Stowing away?
来，坐下来，慢慢说
Sit down!
我是张海棠的女儿，我爸爸出事了
I'm Cheung's daughter. He's in trouble.
想找你帮忙救他
Would you help me save him?
你是张伯的女儿啊
You're Cheung's daughter.
以前我见过你啊
I'd seen you before
脱光了衣服，在家洗澡的时候
You were bathing naked.
我还拧过你的屁股呢
I caressed you
把你给弄哭了
and you cried!
幸亏你爸爸不在家
It was lucky that your dad wasn't there.
要是说起张伯他…
Talking about Uncle Cheung...
我爸爸让罗万成抓去了
My dad was taken by Big Brother Shing.
先喝杯茶
Have some tea first!
来，慢慢说，叙旧嘛，干吗那么焦急？
Why so hurry! Speak slowly and calmly!
你可否帮我把我爸爸救出来？
Would you help me save my dad?
张伯的事我也听说了
I've heard about Cheung's case...
至于谁对谁错，我不管
I don't care who's right or wrong.
罗万成这个人很难对付，谁都知道的
But everyone knows that Big Brother Shing is a tough one!
在道上要讲规矩
We have rules to obey.
我会帮自己的弟兄
We have to help our own men!
我找不到什么理由帮你啊
But I find no reason to help you!
漂亮小妞就不同了
But there's exception for beautiful girls.
有两种女人，我一定要帮
There are two kinds of women that I'll help!
要么是我老妈，要么是我马子
One is my mother and the others are my whores.
你跟我老妈沾不上边啦
You are not my mother.
求我帮你，就是我马子啦
So you have to be my whore if you want me to help you.
你他妈的
Go to hell!
神爷！
Godfather Shen!
你不是来找我吗？
Aren't you coming for me?
怎么没见面就走？
Why leaving so soon?
她是张海棠的女儿
She is Cheung's daughter.
我知道，这么有性格，你让她去陪客
I know! And you treat her as a whore.
不是大材小用了吗？
How tasteless.
我看得起你，给你一个机会跟着我
I am offering you this chance to be my woman.
你认为怎么样？
What do you think?
好好的考虑考虑，千万不要勉强
Think carefully! I won't force you!
罗万成那个老小子，够阴险的
Big Brother Shing is bad news.
张伯这次算是倒霉了
Cheung is in a great trouble this time.
掉在他的手里
Once in his hands,
随时会没命
no chance of survival.
张伯的年纪那么大了，熬不过啊
Cheung's too old. He can't survive this.
这老命八成要玩完啊
Chances are he'll die.
就算捡回一条命，也好受不到哪儿去
He'll suffer a lot even if he is alive!
再来个断手断脚的，这辈子就交待啦
He may lose one of his legs or arms!
真是临老走霉运
Bloody old fool.
神爷！
Godfather Shen!
阿列！
Rick!
怎么才来啊？没事吧？
Why are you so late? Is it alright?
你爸爸呢？
Where's your dad?
他来不了
He can't come!
不过你不用担心，有人罩着他
But don't worry! He's under protection!
我爸爸叫你先走，他不会有事的
He wants you to leave! He's alright!
那你呢？
Then what about you?
我要留下来陪我爸爸
I'll stay here with dad!
待我办妥了这儿的事，会过来找你
I'll come to you after I've finished the work here!
别忘了写信给我！
Don't forget to write me letters!
那我也不走了！
Then I won't leave either!
不行，警察查到你的车，正在通缉你
No way! The police learned of your license plate number.
你一定要走
You must leave!
你放心，我们不会有事
We'll be alright! Don't worry!
先吃饭吧，船快来了
Have some food first! The ship will come soon!
这么快？
So soon?
是啊，王伯已经安排好了
Yes, Uncle Wong had arranged everything!
阿列，你穿的衣服，要用的东西
Rick, here're clothes and other things
我全替你收拾好了
that I prepared for you!
慢慢吃嘛，还有时间呢，小心噎着
Take it easy! There's still time!
你没事吧？
Are you alright?
没有！
Nothing!
我在担心，你一个人走那么远
I'm worrying that you're alone.
放心吧，阿立，这算不了什么！
Don't worry! I can handle it!
我这么聪明，到哪儿都混得起来
I'm smart enough to survive at anywhere!
好好照顾自己啊！
Take care of yourself!
你也是！
You too.
待会儿穿上这件大衣
Put on this overcoat later!
出了海，风会很大的
The wind is strong in the ocean.
阿列…
Rick...
告诉你爸，我走了
Say goodbye for me to your dad!
阿列！
Rick!
快过来，我等你
Come over! I wait for you!
别逼我娶菲律宾妞儿啊！
I don't want to marry a Pilipino woman!
这么早就来了，祥老大
Big Brother Cheung!
别糗我了，良哥
Don't make fun of me.
立姐，祥哥！
Miss Lap, Mr. Cheung!
大小姐！
Miss Lap!
爸，你又喝酒？
Dad, are you drinking again?
我已经叫你不要喝了
I've told you not to drink!
不喝酒，还叫我干什么？
What else can I do if I don't drink?
不要给他酒，给他参茶
Don't give him liquor. Give him Ginseng tea!
阿立，今天让我喝一次嘛
Let me drink another cup!
不许喝！
No way!
我是不是太过份了？
Am I driving him too far?
你也是为他好嘛
You're doing that for his good!
他前几天刚刚洗完胃
He had his stomach washed just a few days ago.
医生都叫他不要再喝酒了
The doctor had told him not to drink.
你替我看着他
Look after him for me please!
阿立，过来…来
Lap, come here...
我给你介绍几位日本大老板
Let me introduce you to some Japanese tycoons.
我来介绍，这位是田中先生
This is Mr. Tanaka.
您好，干杯！
How do you do?
这位是山本先生
This is Mr. Yamamoto.
您好！
How do you do?
干杯！
Cheers!
这位是西都先生
This is Mr. Saito.
您好！
How do you do?
给我一杯酒，阿祥！
Give me some liquor, Cheung!
想喝酒吗，张伯？
Do you want a drink, Uncle Cheung?
来，这是孝敬您的
This one is for you.
阿立姐说，不能让他喝
Miss Lap said that he could not drink.
是吗？你听见没有？
Really! Haven't you heard of that?
你女儿多疼你啊，叫你别喝啦
Your daughter loves you very much!
阿立说说罢了
She didn't mean what she said.
你真的这么想喝酒啊？
Do you really want to drink so much?
料哥！
Brother Liu!
不如这样，你蹲下来
Why don't you kneel down
藏在我下边，我倒给你喝！
and hide under me? I pour the drink to you!
你女儿不就看不见了吗
Then your daughter won't see it!
好…
Good idea!
料哥！
Brother Liu!
好酒量…
You can drink!
张开嘴！
Open your mouth!
好喝吧
Taste good, huh?
不但人漂亮，唱得更好
She is a beauty and a drinker.
我唱得不好，请多多包涵
I sang poorly.
张伯，不如走吧！
Uncle Cheung, let's go!
阿立！
Lap!
我回去陪您喝好吗？
Let me drink with you at home?
好…
Good...
来…
Come on...
神爷，好久不见，干杯！
Godfather Shen, long time no see!
干杯！
Cheers!
坐下来慢慢聊嘛
Please sit down and talk awhile.
好！
Good!
你那位搭挡刘胖子的事情怎么样了？
How's thing going with your partner, Fat Lau?
没牵连到你吧？
Would it give you any trouble?
应该不会，他很够意思
I don't think it would! He won't do any harm to me.
不对吧！
No, he isn't.
我最近收到风声
I've heard that
他已经变成警方的污点证人
he's turned police's witness now.
还打算把你的事情全都说出来了
He's going to tell all the things about you!
并且要干掉你啊
And he's going to finish you.
还是小心一点好！
You'd better watch out!
神爷，我要干掉你
Godfather Shen, I'll finish you.
没事…他不小心摔了一跤
It's alright... He tumbled.
没事…
It's alright...
车就停在那边
The car is over there.
我不要坐神爷的车
I don't want to take Godfather Shen's car.
好…我们坐计程车好吗？
Ok! We'll take a taxi!
好啦，你进去看着阿立
You go to look after Lap.
我先送你回去
I take you home first!
我没事，你进去看着阿立吧，我没事
I'm alright. Go look after her!
张伯，你真的没事吧？
Uncle Cheung, are you really alright?
你马上给我找个可靠的人
Find me a reliable man at once,
趁刘胖子出庭之前杀了他
and go to kill Fat Lau before he goes to the court.
千万不能失手
No failure!
好！
Good!
来一杯Vodka Tonic
Give me a glass of Vodka Tonic.
先生，谢谢二十块
20 dollars, please!
谢谢！
Thanks!
阿列，你好
Dear Rick.
香港很冷，不知道你那边怎么样
Hong Kong is cold! How's the weather in Philippine?
阿列，你说你已经全都安顿好了
You've told me that you'd settled down already,
而且已经开始适应那边的生活了
and began to adapt to the lifestyle there.
那我就放心了
I was happy about that.
我爸已经没事了
Dad was alright.
酒吧也让给人家了
But the bar was sold.
一切好像要重新再来一样
We seemed to have to start all over again.
你问我何时到菲律宾找你
You asked me when I would come to you.
我的答案会让你很失望
My answer may upset you.
我已经决定不过去了
I've decided not coming to Philippine.
你走了之后
After your leaving,
我曾经冷静想过
I've thought calmly and thoroughly.
其实我们的性格有很大的不同
There's a great difference between our personality.
干脆趁着这个机会，大家算啦
We'd better break up, seizing this moment.
无谓再拖下去了
It's worthless to carry on such a relation.
希望你安心在那边发展
Wish you have a stable living and development.
不要再惦记我，好好保重
Just forget me and take care of yourself.
阿立
Yours sincerely, Lap.
对不起，忘了拿打火机
Sorry, I've forgot my lighter!
阿祥，你喜欢这里吗？
Do you like this place?
这儿不错啊
Not bad!
以前这儿更好
This place was better in the past.
以前是我爸爸开的
My dad ran this place before.
那时候我很开心的
I was very happy at that time.
你现在也蛮好的
You're living fine now also.
你小时候开不开心？
Did you enjoy your childhood?
当然开心了，我外婆很疼我的
Of course, my grandma loved me very much!
那个时候我喜欢看电影
I liked watching movie very much at that time.
她知道我没钱，假装让我陪她看
She knew I had no money so she pretended to watch movie
她是为了满足我
and asked me to come with her.
一进电影院她就睡着了
But she felt asleep at the minute she went into the cinema.
你外婆还在不在？
Is you grandma still living?
在，不过她老了
She is still living, but very old.
阿祥，你活到这么大
Cheung, after all these years,
有没有真正喜欢一个人？
have you really loved any one?
即使说有，你也不会相信
You won't believe that...
还想着以前的男朋友？
Are you thinking of your past boyfriend?
算了，立姐，你们这么多年没见，什么都变了
Everything must have changed after so many years of departure.
你不会明白
You won't understand!
如果你真的喜欢一个人
If you really love someone,
你会永远想着他
you'll think of him forever.
既然如此，你过去找他吧
Then you would go to find him!
怎么找？
Where could I find him?
算了，立姐，还是忘了他吧
Just forget him!
他人真的很好
He's really quite a guy.
这条链子就是他送给我的
This is the bracelet he gave me!
我一直戴到现在
I'm wearing it until now!
你可不要告诉神爷啊
You mustn't tell Godfather Shen about it!
我真想看看他到底长成什么样子
I really want to know how he looks.
你把他夸得这么好
You've said so many good words about him.
我真的有点嫉妒
I am really jealous.
不，当我没说过
No, I didn't say anything.
阿祥，如果我有机会再见他
If I could meet him again,
我一定会跟他走
I would leave with him!
那时候你会不会帮我？
Would you help me leave?
到时候再说吧
I don't know. Let's wait and see.
会不会帮我？
Would you help me?
我不知道
I don't know!
你会帮我的
You will.
都这么多年了
After all these years,
说不定人家结了婚，生了孩子呢
he might have married already.
四点开庭，这么早就他妈去
The court hold at 4! Why so early?
早知道那么麻烦，我就不做证人了
I wouldn't be the witness if I knew it's annoying.
这次麻烦你，拜托帮帮忙！
Please give us a hand, Mr. Lau!
不是看在曹警司份上
If not because of lnspector Tso,
跪下求我，我也不去啊！
I won't go even if you kneel down.
开车！
Start!
你什么时候回来的？
When were you back?
昨天晚上
Last night!
你刚才这么匆忙，有事吗？
Why were you in such a hurry just now?
我今天就走
I'm leaving today.
去哪儿？回菲律宾？
Where will you go? Philippine?
你现在去哪儿？我送你！
Where are you going? I'll give you a ride!
我在前面下车
Could I get off at there?
阿列
Rick!
有没有空？我们去喝杯东西
Let's have a drink, should we?
我有事要跟你说
I have something to talk to you.
说吧！
Just say it!
没话说吗？
Nothing to say?
其实你要说的，这封信已经全说了
Actually what you want to say is all written in this letter.
还给你
Take it back!
- 喂  - 马列吗？
- Hello!  - Is it Rick Ma?
是
Yes.
我是阿料，今晚行程有变动吗？
It's Liu. Is there any change in tonight's schedule?
没有
No.
那我们准时在菜市码头见
Then we'll meet on time at the pier.
好
Ok.
- 我可否进来？ - 我赶时间
- Can I come in?  - I have no time.
你放心，我不会耽误你很久
Don't worry, I won't take you too much time.
阿列，我知道这几年你过得不容易
Rick, I know you suffered a lot all these years.
我怎么过与你无关
It's none of your business!
阿列，对不起！
I'm sorry, Rick!
用不着说对不起
There's no need to say sorry.
你没什么对不起我的
You have done nothing to be sorry!
我知道我没去找你，你生我的气
You're angry because I didn't come to you, I know.
都过去啦！
What was done was done!
是吗？
Really?
你回去吧，时间到了，我该走了
It's time for you to go back! And me too.
没想到我等了这么久
I've been waiting for so long
你连一个机会都不给我
but you didn't give me a chance.
你等我？
Were you waiting for me?
当初我走的时候，你答应过我什么？
What had you promised me when I was leaving?
我在那边等了这么久，我又等到什么？
What had I got then by waiting there for so long?
你听我说！
Listen to me!
算了，阿立，谁对谁错根本没有意义
It's meaningless to discuss who's right or wrong.
即使你不想听，我也要说
You must listen to me even if you don't want to.
出事那天晚上，我爸爸被罗万成抓了
That night at the accident, my dad was caught by Law.
为了救爸爸，我去找神爷
I went to Godfather Shen to ask for help.
我没告诉你
I didn't tell you.
是怕你留下来不肯走，怕你出事
I didn't want you to stay and get involved.
神爷答应帮我，但是要我跟他
Godfather Shen promised to help if I agreed to follow him.
为了救我爸，我没法子不跟他
For the sake of dad, I had to agree!
神爷这个人不简单
Godfather Shen is a man of power.
我知道这辈子我们不能在一起了
I knew we'd never stay together
我写信给你，是让你死了这条心
so I wrote to you to change your mind.
我不希望你再这么等下去
I didn't want you to wait for me!
我虽然人跟着神爷
Although I lived with Godfather Shen,
但是我的心一直想着你
I thought of you all the time.
这几年来，我过得很乱
In these years, my life is chaotic.
爸最近去世了，我才开始有点希望
My dad died recently and my life starts to change.
我好想去找你
I want to find you.
刚才碰见你，我很开心
I was very happy when I met you again.
以为我们可以再在一起了
I thought we could stay together again.
可能已经过去了，真的不能再回头
Maybe time passed could never come back.
阿列，你保重！
Rick, take care of yourself!
出门啊？
Are you leaving?
什么事啊？
Do you have business to do?
What is it?
你好急吗？赶时间啊？
Are you in a hurry?
我刚刚有空，特地上来看看你嘛
I was free just now so I come to see you.
对不起，我没时间，你自己慢慢坐吧
Sorry, I have no time to stay with you!
不至于吧，聊几句都没空吗？
Don't you have time for just a few words?
你想怎么样？
What do you want?
如果让神爷知道的话，他怎么想？
What will Godfather Shen do if he knows this?
那我可得问问他啦
Then I must ask him for that.
我打个电话问问他
I must phone him.
料哥，这么认真干吗？开玩笑嘛
Don't take it so serious? I was only joking.
我也是开玩笑啊
I was joking too.
出来混，大家志在开心，对吗？
We all want happiness, don't we?
太认真会伤和气
We'll spoil everything if we take it too serious.
料哥，有什么话就直说吧
Just say what you want!
爽快，我就喜欢你这么有性格
Straightforward! I like this character of you.
咱们开门见山
Ok, let's be frank!
是不是赶去码头会情夫？
Are you going to the pier for your lover?
旧相好吗？
An old boyfriend?
谁说的，你别听人家乱说，料哥
Who said that? Stop bullshitting!
我只是去旅行
I am only going for travel.
是吗？
Really?
对了，你来了这么久，我还没倒茶给你
I forgot your tea for such a long time!
我们喝杯茶再说吧
Let's have some time first!
这才像话，别老是赶我走
That's right! Don't always kick me out!
别走！
Don't go.
所谓一家便宜两家沾，你想跟他走，我让你走
I'll let you go if you give me benefit
不会告诉神爷
and I won't tell Godfather Shen.
不过，我有什么好处呢？
But, what can I have?
不知道你胡说什么
What are you talking about?
话说得太白就没意思了
It's no need to say all out!
我对你怎么样，咱们大家心照不宣
You know that I treat you kind.
这件事要是说出来
If I inform Godfather Shen about that,
别说是你，连他妈那小子也不好受
you and that guy will be both in trouble.
乖乖的，大家开心，行吗？
Let's enjoy a while together, ok?
料哥！
Liu!
你来得正好，她想溜啊！
It's good that you've come. She wanted to escape.
幸亏让我知道了，及时阻止她
I just came in time to stop her.
你看着她，我打个电话给神爷
Watch her! I go to call Godfather Shen.
看着她别让她溜啊
Keep your eyes on her.
发生什么事啊？
What happened really?
阿列回来了，我要跟他走
Rick was back, I want to leave with him.
喂，神爷，赖料啊
Hello, Godfather Shen. It's Lai Liu speaking.
阿祥，你一定要帮我
Cheung, you must help me.
有好戏看啦
Trouble will come!
神爷就在附近，马上到
Godfather Shen will be right here.
神爷，坐！
Please sit down!
发生什么事？
What is going on?
阿立她想…
She wanted...
神爷，赖料想强奸我
Liu wanted to rape me.
没有这回事
It's not true.
给我天大的胆子，我也不敢
I didn't have that guts to do this.
她想跟着旧相好跑掉，被我截住了
She wanted to see her boyfriend but I stopped her.
您看看她，行李都收拾好了
She had her luggage all packed up.
神爷，他胡说！
He's lying.
我胡说？那小子，还真巧啦
That guy... It's really coincident.
就是我们从菲律宾请回来的
He's the guy employed from Philippine.
今天我去监视刘胖子
Today when I kept an eye on Lau,
无意中发现那小子是她的旧情人
I discovered unintentiously about this.
阿立！
Lap!
有没有这回事？
Is it the truth?
有！
Yes!
神爷，我已经跟了你那么多年
I had followed you for so many years.
以前我欠你的，应该还清了
I had paid you back probably.
就让我走吧！
Would you let me go?
这次我下了决心要走
I've decided firmly to leave.
你那么多女人
You have so many women.
多我一个不多，少我一个也不少啊
It won't affect you without me!
那小子呢？
What about that guy?
放心吧！
Don't worry!
您吩咐过，事成之后就把他干掉
You've told me to kill him after the work has finished.
我全都布置好了！
I've already arranged everything!
你真的想走？
Do you really want to leave?
对！
Yes.
既然你的心不在我这儿
Since you didn't have your heart on me,
我留你也没什么用
it's no use to make you stay.
不过便宜外人，不如便宜自己弟兄
But I'd rather benefit my own people.
阿料
Liu!
我知道你一直对她很感兴趣
I know you've been loving her for times.
那我就便宜你了，上啊！
I'll give you a favor!
你简直不是人
You are not human being.
不错，我是神
Yes, I'm God.
这个世界是我的，你不服气？
Everybody is under my control!
阿料，还不上！
Liu, go ahead!
学着点儿，小子！
Learn a lesson, young man!
神爷，不要！
No, boss!
神爷，你就放了她吧
Boss, please release her!
你神经病啊，把枪放下！
Are you crazy? Put down the gun!
我叫你放下枪！
I told you to put it down!
快走，立姐！
Go away, be quick!
阿祥！
Cheung!
我不想这样的
I don't mean to do this.
不过，你实在太过份了
But you are driving her too far.
不需要弄出人命嘛
Don't hurt anybody!
她一直对你很好，服侍你这么多年
She treated you so good for years.
你就让她走吧
please let her go!
干吗还要逼她呢？
Why do you have to hurt her still?
我叫你把枪放下
Put down the gun!
神爷，我的手发抖，很容易走火
I'm trembling and I can't control the gun.
我不想打伤您，您不要逼我
I may hurt you accidentally.
立姐！
Lap!
对不起，神爷，我不能够不救她
Sorry, I have to save her!
人不能见死不救，是不是？
I can't stand watching her dying!
立姐！…
Lap!...
快去按电梯
Get the lift quickly!
对不起，神爷！
Sorry, boss!
待我送走立姐，我会回来向你道歉
After I send her away, I'll be back for your forgiving.
阿祥，你胆敢背叛我？
Don't you dare to betray me?
没有！
No!
我想救立姐，我没有背叛你
I just wanted to save her, not to betray you.
阿祥，电梯来了
Cheung, the lift is coming.
神爷，别生我气
Don't be angry about me!
他就在里面等你
He's waiting inside for you.
对不起，阿祥，我连累了你
Sorry to cause you such a trouble.
别这么说，立姐！
Don't mention it!
看见你好，我也开心
I'm glad to make you happy.
最重要是你安全
I worry your safety most.
你对我这么好，真不知道怎么感谢你
You're so kind to me. I didn't know what to say.
你保重！
Take care of yourself!
你自己也要小心啊
You too!
你回去吧！
You should go now!
阿列！
Rick!
你的嘴怎么啦？
What happened to your mouth?
没什么，刚才太匆忙，不小心撞了一下
It's alright! I got hurled carelessly.
上船吧！
Get on the ship!
阿列，你怎么样？
Rick, are you alright?
立姐，你怎么样？
Lap, are you alright?
别开枪！自己人，是自己人
Don't shoot! We're friends!
他是我朋友
He's my friend.
立姐！
Lap!
阿祥，你怎么还没走？
Why haven't you left?
我怕你出事
I'm worrying about your safety.
阿列，你怎么样？
Rick, are you alright?
阿祥，快过来帮忙！
Give me a hand, Cheung!
你就是列哥？我叫阿祥
You must be Rick! I'm Cheung!
我早就听过你的名字
I've heard about you before.
你伤成这样，赶快找医生才行啊
You're hurt so badly! You must see a doctor!
不用了！
No, it's alright.
我认识一个大陆医生
I know a doctor came from China.
不要紧，阿祥是自己人
He's on our side.
他怎么样？医生！
How is he, doctor?
你叫我彭叔好了，他没什么，不要紧
Just call me Pang! He's alright!
人老了真没用了
I'm old and useless now.
你看看，我把东西都遗留在车上了
I forgot my tools in the car!
你看着他，我去拿！
Take care of him! I go to get my tools!
阿立，把钥匙交给阿祥，帮我把东西拿来
Give him the key and tell him to get me something.
阿祥！
Cheung!
阿列想请你帮他拿点东西
He wanted you to get something for him
在世华会七十六号储物箱里
at Cabinet no. 76 at Club Siwa.
这些让我来做好了
Let me do these.
今天晚上真是谢谢你
Thank you so much for tonight.
别这么客气了，立姐！
Don't mention it!
你看我这个脑子，又忘了东西
I forgot my tools again!
你拿点棉花给他擦伤口，我出去拿东西
You go to clean his wound with some cotton.
你还戴着它
Why are you still wearing it?
当时送你你不要，扔了之后，自己又捡回来
You refused it when I gave you, but picked it back later.
喂，神爷，我是阿彭啊
Hello, I'm Pang!
你们的人怎么到现在还没有来啊？
Why didn't your men come still?
是…对…
Yes... Right...
好，我尽量拖着他们
Ok, I try to make them stay.
阿列！
Rick!
是不是这儿？
Is it here?
我下车看看
I go and see.
我以前就是在这里打死那个警察
I had killed a policeman here before.
阿列，不要再提以前的事了
Rick, it's already passed away.
想不到又回到这儿
I came back again now!
如果当初没发生那件事
If that murder didn't happen,
不知道现在会怎么样呢
I wonder what will become now
你有没有后悔回来？
Do you regret to come back?
有些事，我从来没后悔过
I've never regretted on something.
里面一个人也没有
There's no one inside.
看来没人住，我看挺安全的
I think it's empty and be quite safe.
来，进去吧！
Let's get in!
立姐，别忘了东西
Don't forget the things!
我小时候看见外婆生病
When I was young and saw grandma was ill,
就很想当医生
I wanted to be a doctor.
真是想也没想到…
I don't even imagine that...
谁知道以后会发生什么事呢？
Who knows what will happen?
列哥，菲律宾有很多杀手，是吗？
Rick, are there many killers in Philippine?
干你们这一行要冷酷无情啊
You have to be cold blooded in this trade.
你看得电影太多了…
You've watched too many movies...
那倒不是，起码你们不受人气
No, actually you are not badly treated.
神爷这个人怎么样？
How is Godfather Shen like?
这位老大可难侍候了
He's difficult to work with.
你永远都不知道他在想什么
You never know what he thinks.
我真佩服立姐，能忍耐他那么久
I think Lap is great to have tolerated him for so long.
要是让我整天对着不喜欢的人
If I have to face someone I don't like,
我情愿死了算了
I would rather die.
你的伤口好像发炎了
Your wound seems to be inflamed.
用刀切开伤口，把子弹弄出来
Cut the wound and take the bullet out.
那可很痛的
That's painful.
来，咬着它
Bite it.
不用了，我承受得来
No, I can stand it.
就这么弄啊？
Like this?
怎么啦？
What happened?
闭上眼睛
Close your eyes.
不用，来吧！
No, come on!
干你们这行，可真够绝
Doing your job must be strong.
阿立，你先出去
Lap, you go out first.
我要帮忙
I want to help.
不用了，立姐，我一个人可以了
No, I can manage myself.
阿祥，你有没有想过将来干什么？
Cheung, have you thought about your future?
光棍儿一条，想什么想？
No, not worth thinking.
如果有个女人要你照顾呢？
What if you have a woman to take care of?
女人？我外婆啊？
Woman? My grandmother?
阿立，万一我出了什么事，你帮我照顾她
Lap, if I have any accident. Please look after her.
你答不答应？
Do you promise?
好！
Yes!
子弹已经拿出来了
The bullet is taken out.
船大概下午可以到达，好！
The ship will arrive in the afternoon!
喂，七二五四一
725, 12.
你外婆找你，叫你打神爷的手提电话
Your grandmother told you to call her with Godfather Shen's phone.
喂，神爷啊！
Hello, Godfather Shen!
阿祥，你在外边蛮过瘾的吧？
Cheung, you seem to be enjoying yourself out there!
有个人很想念你
Somebody is missing you.
喂，阿祥…你留下那么多钱干什么？
Cheung, why are you leaving so much money?
外婆，你怎么样？
How are you, grandmother?
我没什么，我担心你有什么事
I'm alright. I'm just worrying about you.
你们老板说，你好几天没上班了
Your boss said you haven't been to work for some days.
到底什么事啊？
What happened?
阿祥，阿立呢？
Cheung, where's Lap?
我不知道！
I don't know!
不知道？那算了！
No? Forget it!
与我外婆无关，神爷…
There's nothing to do with my grandmother...
找我吗？立姐？
Are you looking for me? Lap?
对不起，阿祥！
Sorry, Cheung!
千万别说这些
Don't say such things.
外婆在神爷手里？
Godfather Shen has captured grandmother?
不要紧，我回去好了
Never mind. I'll go back.
没用的，别傻了
Don't be silly.
你已经帮了我这么多
You've helped me so much.
我帮助你并不是为了让你感激我
I help you not because I want you to feel grateful.
快和列哥走吧！
Run away with Rick!
要救外婆出来
Save grandmother.
神爷要的是你，不是我外婆
Godfather Shen wants you, not my grandmother.
你忍耐了那么久，难得有机会跑出来
It's a valuable chance to have escaped.
千万不能回去
Don't go back.
阿祥，我认识你这么久
Cheung, I've known you for so long.
你对别人友善，我怎么会不知道呢
I know that you are very nice.
但这次不是小事，神爷会杀了你啊
This time is different. Godfather Shen will kill you.
认识这么久，只知道我对别人友善而已？
You only know that I am nice to others?
阿祥，我知道你的感受
Cheung, I know what you feel.
你觉得我怎么样？
What do you think about me?
是不是把我当作是你弟弟啊？
You only treat me as your brother?
是啊，所以你外婆就是我外婆
Yes, so your grandmother is my grandmother.
有些事不是你看的那么简单
Things are not as simple as you think.
喜欢一个人，又不可以跟他在一起，是很痛苦的
It's painful if you can't be with your loved one.
我知道
I know.
所以你要和列哥走，我留下
So you should go with Rick.
就算我肯让你留下，列哥也不会愿意
Rick won't let you stay either.
只要你愿意，我会跟他说
I'll speak to him if you wish.
阿祥啊…
Cheung...
立姐，我根本没有打算跟你们一起走
Lap, I never plan to run away with you.
你们走后，我有办法让神爷慢慢忘记这件事
I'll make Godfather Shen forget this matter after you leave.
他很照顾我的
He takes care of me.
我没事的，放心吧！
I'll be alright!
列哥，你跟立姐走，我不想跟你们一起去
Rick, you go with Lap. I don't wanna go with you.
你开什么玩笑？
Are you kidding?
我说真的
No, I mean it.
阿立，他怎么了？
Lap, what's wrong with him?
没什么大不了，我不喜欢菲律宾
Philippines isn't my ideal place.
而且这件事与我无关
And it's none of my business.
我没必要走，我喜欢香港
I love Hong Kong so I don't have to go.
阿祥，有话直说，不要放在心里
Cheung, just say what you wanna say.
如果当我是朋友，说出来大伙儿一起解决吧
If you treat me as friend, just say it. We solve the problem together.
有些事根本不能解决
Some problems can't be solved.
- 阿列  - 立姐
- Rick  - Lap
到底怎么回事？
What's the matter?
有些事不知道比知道好
You'd better ignore it.
说出来大家都没意思
It's no use to talk out.
总之你不走，全都不要走
If you don't go, all of us will stay.
阿列
Rick
说！
Say it!
阿祥他…
Chueng...
阿祥
Cheung
放了我外婆！
Let my grandma go.
你怎么这么没规矩？
How come you are so bold?
这样跟我说话
How dare you talk to me in this way?
我还有事，外婆你先回去吧
I have to do other stuff. You go back first.
送外婆回去
Accompany her.
阿祥，你们老板人真好
Cheung, you boss is such a good guy.
还请我吃西瓜，你可要好好做事
He even treated me watermelon. You should work hard.
一个人？
Alone?
就你一个人回来？
You come back alone?
何必为一个女人弄得这么严重？
Why do you have to make trouble because of a woman?
好样的，出一出去就充老大
That's awesome. You become the leader now.
教训我？
Give me a lesson?
神爷，立姐已经不在香港了
Godfather Shen, Lap has left Hong Kong already.
上哪儿去了？
Where did she go?
说！
Say it!
不知道，我真的不知道
I don't know. I really don't know.
我知道他一定不会放过阿祥
I know he won't let Cheung go.
我们不应该丢下他
We shouldn't leave him behind.
可我又那么想跟你一起走
But I do want to go with you.
等了那么多年才等到今天
For the coming of this day, I have been waiting for years.
怎么会弄成这样？
How come it result in this way?
本来就与他无关
It's none of his business
跟你去菲律宾那次一样
just like that time you went to Philippines.
这种事怎么又发生呢？
How come it happen again?
我害了他，是我害了他
It's my fault. I get him involved.
我们俩回去
We go back.
神爷，电话，是大小姐
Godfather Shen, phone call from Miss Lap.
阿祥，快过来
Cheung, come here quickly.